[Music]
uh apart from uh spending time in the
application security business and also
focusing on cloud security I'm a code
scanning nerd uh you'll see this in a
couple of slides I feel uh I've spent uh
inor amount of time learning the various
ways in which a code needs to be
interpreted and understood um that um is
a skill I can only use in my job um and
uh I'm looking forward to sharing a lot
of uh uh dos and don'ts and a lot of
pitfalls of some of the approaches that
we try to take here at buz um let me um
also in terms of housekeeping um if you
want to track buzz in how we um operate
today can check out our website at b.co
you can follow uh me uh on GitHub and my
team um on LinkedIn and Twitter uh
that's where we share most of our
research findings and uh some of the
progress we've made so
far um so this talk is called ordering
files for AI assisted development and uh
we're essentially going to cover um an
interesting uh set of uh uh research uh
initiatives we took here internally ever
since starting buz about a year ago and
um
as of I mean if you if you are listening
to this talk you may not be surprised
one of the um most promising
applications of large language models
has been Cod generation uh we've seen
this uh in our previous companies
working on solving problems in the
security space um and we're now taking
that and scaling that up and
generalizing some of the approaches that
we've taken previously to see how we can
uh help teams uh perform code reviews in
the age of AI using these uh these
amazing
tools so this talk will get very
technical very fast so we'll start
really um putting up some uh basic
premises to get us uh going a few
analogies that we'll use along the
way the first one uh is a code grammar
uh so even before we dive into ordering
files and specifically in the context of
code review um we should uh take a look
at code and code grammar and see what it
brings to the table I mean um ever since
I learned how to program uh initially on
python I love this analogy that coding
is uh very much like driving even before
autonomous um and uh that uh struct and
the grammar of python can really serve
as a set of traffic signals for us to be
able to understand and read code and
this is a very simplified example where
I took a bunch of uh traffic signs that
we all know and fairly simply understand
and um they all actually have within our
code uh specific meanings in the form of
structs um input validation for a stop
sign where the input validation acts
like a stop signing code it's ensuring
inputs that are uh defined uh as
criteria proceeding before errors and
crashes um and you can look through
these examples not to spend too much
time on them but I think it's an
interesting way to think about the
Unseen part of code uh you you'll see me
talk about the implicit and the explicit
areas of code even when it's not um you
know kind of neatly displayed on a
single file or on multiple files code is
going to have a lot of um uh various uh
grammar components that are going to
take uh into account as code is either
executed interpolated or compiled um and
we'll talk about what those mean in a
couple of
minutes specifically when I focus on AI
coding and this is everything with uh
that has to do with coding agents and
how we think about using Frontier models
to understand codee base code bases
better and use you know these great
capabilities of how these these new
generation of lmms understand code to be
able to perform coding tasks and um I
really love this 4x4 grid I use it all
the time to you know kind of organize my
thoughts on how uh we should or we could
uh Implement these llms for a variety of
use cases when we think about
incorporating LMS into specific
workflows within um within developer
flows um so my XS goes between code
completion kind of very straightforward
give me the next components uh help me
complete this uh code that I've already
begun to write and all the way goes uh
to the right side to code generation
this is where sometimes my starting
point won't be existing code would be an
idea uh as an example um my y AIS
includes the use cases in which I want
AI to have more control um this is where
I can use things like agentic workflows
to um take multiple steps in order to
plan spec and then evaluate and execute
the code that I plan to write and on the
bottom we have kind of the current
mature model for co-pilots where
developers are in control they can use
tab to accept a recommendation um or uh
we can uh refine through a chat
interface what exactly we want the code
to do and you can see that grammar
actually matters for all of these use
cases and the fact that llms understand
grammar um already help us especially in
this uh top uh excuse me this bottom uh
left quartile um where we're mostly
focusing on code completion using
co-pilots and we're mostly relying on
human in the loop to be able to enforce
and provide uh the feedback that's
required to accept results you can see
that as we progress to both generation
and uh areas in which we want to AI to
take more control um the use cases
become more interesting in the sense of
being able to use either past context or
existing context in in a specific code
base or project to be able to provide
additional um coding uh coding elements
and this is where things get really
interesting for grammar because on one
end we want um you know AI to be able to
take control even maybe to write code
better better than us but on the other
we wanted to continue and maintain the
conventions of a past project and uh the
promise here could be one of a variety
of uh interesting um uh research areas
uh two that we won't focus on today one
is reasoning models um that can kind of
create these chains of thoughts of
different uh questions about how code
should be composed before providing the
eventual
result and the second one is mostly
around increasing uh the context window
so uh we assume and we've seen early
results of that that if we cram an
entire code base to a model that's
susceptible for uh for that amount of um
of tokens uh we can really ask it
anything and get uh consistent results
and the model doesn't get lazy or tired
um as you might uh sometimes find out
when you use some of the commercial off
the shelf or some of the smaller models
on hugging face uh those are the two we
won't be uh talking about today we'll
talk about an area of research that's
slightly overlooked and even you can
think of it as kind of almost low cost
uh which is just uh changing the order
in which we feed data into a model uh so
this has kind of semblance to this idea
of a Chain of Thought
but it also utilizes the fact that we
can use other tools uh to figure out
code grammar before we cram it into um
into our context
window if you think about it today uh
grammar already makes all of our
developer tools work um so when we look
at our IDE um it uses a uh language
server protocol and it helps us find go
from definitions to references and
navigate uh within our project based on
uh the ability to identify these node uh
cross node relationships across files
for a variety of different languages uh
you can use plugins you can use a local
server protocol um and that's generally
how you navigate within a codebase in
your IDE
today um when you think about package
managers uh this is your npm most recent
uh Bond um and and and cargo and Maven
and everything that you you need to get
a product Set uh excuse me your project
set up with a required dependency
it builds a dependency graph uh there's
different ways to build a dependency
graph but the end result is quite the
same we want to use um the dependency
manager grammar um to import a subset of
packages that's required to the project
and nothing more uh some languages do
this better than others um and that's an
area that we've already seen a lot of
improvement when it comes to um giving
models only the correct set of
dependencies instead of giving them
everything that we've ever wished to
import
my last example uh quite non-trivial is
actually cloud and my background in
infrastructure is code infrastructure is
code languages like um terraform from
Hashi Corp cloud formation from AWS they
all use a graph back end that describes
the different relationships between
resources that then enables me when I
want to make changes to see only the
incremental change without destroying
elements of my infrastructure that
aren't supposed to be impacted by a
change uh if you think about it's quite
quite the most impressive or elegant
implementation of of grammar um in in
our modern stack it really uh makes
changes much more seamless compared to
when we think about application
code so what problem are we trying to
tackle uh we're tackling the problem of
pull requests uh pull requests whether
we like it we like it or not are the
main convention to introduce code edits
to to our existing code base um but code
doesn't live in isolation when we ask
our peers to evaluate code changes from
a massive project we give them only a
subset of files we
assume that they can see the Matrix
that's how I call it we assume that
they'll be able to interpolate just as a
compiler can or an interpreter can the
different Downstream impact in the blast
radius of a change and uh for humans
it's not easy right if you haven't been
uh at the company for very long or if
you aren't as proficient with with a
programming language and you don't
really understand some areas of the
grammar um then then you won't be able
to comprehend the entire scope of change
maybe maybe you're not supposed to maybe
you're only supposed to understand that
subset but effectively that's not really
the case effectively P requests will
often ignore uh the downstream grammar
they'll give you a subset of code to
evaluate and we'll kind of have our
fingers crossed that other um processes
down Downstream like our cicd or
integration our build systems will help
help us catch these Downstream impacts
that humans um find it harder to to
extrapolate and
evaluate uh one last rant or maybe two
last rants is uh possibly git could have
solved this right so if you think about
G logs and specifically commit messages
think about a world where we can
constantly iterate on Commit messages
and constantly use them to Anchor
changes and make them our context or our
grammar anchor for for understanding
changes within the scope of a commit or
PR um but uh just as uh my man David
Beckham said that's not really the case
right if you open um my code this is
probably the types of commit messages
you'll see uh we don't have uh
sufficient tooling today but we also
don't have uh sufficient processes to
help us make that um that commit uh uh
message back and the the connective
Fabric or connective tissue for
code um there is an interesting area of
that by the way if you're interested uh
the concept of stacking uh could be
stacking combined potentially with uh
with AI maybe for an idea for my next
talk is is an area we're exploring to uh
maybe bridge that Gap as well okay uh
last rant I promise um what do you think
about reading a GitHub PR in order right
if you think about Pro requests you're
probably seeing them on GitHub if I have
to imagine um there's four areas within
the GitHub PR tab where you would
generally go um to understand that the
flow of a change uh you can use the
description tag that's where you have
like this timeline of all of the changes
that have occurred you have your main
description you have all of the um you
know uh your uh your your checks on the
bottom what's kind of the merge blockers
everything you probably need on a time
uh based format you don't see the code
uh that's uh that's not something you'd
see there you'd see all the interaction
of your
teammates um the second aspect is
commits and uh commits again if we would
have organized commits uh and if you're
organization organizes commits in an
amazing way please let me know but
generally um commits are a good place
only to see the incremental change after
you've already reviewed the pr um I
won't spend too much time about checks
not page that I like that much it's
where you go to see the results of of
your CI uh your CI checks usually get
thrown out to get actions tab then you
have to go back out of order but in 90%
of the time you'll spend your time in
this a toz sorted file change Tab and
that's uh that's where most of us spend
our time that's where we look at uh at
coach changes again a subset based on a
g diff and that's how we try to make
sense of it and to be honest I think
that's not good enough right I find it
again my man uh number seven uh David
Beckham uh wants us to be honest this
this process is is difficult and it's
hard to continuously use um these uh
these workflows to see and understand um
the the linearity of a code change uh
because you do see only a subset of it
every on every one of these GitHub
tabs and that's a pro probably the best
best way to describe our motivation for
going on this journey we felt like um we
can take git and GitHub um in the Pro
request process and and dismantle it and
re rebuild it in a new pattern new um a
new um a new order um and the way we
wanted to do that is using um automation
that will essentially read code the same
way that us as humans would read code uh
so you know the you know the best
practice for for is actually to check
out the branch run it locally and look
at the debug logs and errors and and
kind of test it out for yourself and
kind of go through within your ID
through the definitions and references
and look through um all of them um and
that brings me to code indexing or code
directionality that's generally our
starting point for this
journey um so code indexing has been
around for a while right so you've
already seen this if you've been using
an IDE for for the past 12 years or 15
years um this is what gets you from
point A to B within within your IDE um
tools like LSP the language uh server
protocol that's maintained by Microsoft
um the LF which is an improvement on on
that protocol uh GitHub has two project
that kind of go back and forth between
indexing and references called stag
graphs and Tre sitter um Sor graph has a
great project um that uh that's supposed
to kind of solve some of problem that uh
LSPs have and most recently we've had
we've gotten the addition of um of large
language models I'll specifically talk
about open AI 40 model and I know you
can kind of rant that maybe son 3.5 is
better but believe me based on some of
this Empirical research generally we've
gotten the same kind of consistent
results for this type of use case but in
general what I wanted to show you is
that there's generally three ways to
look at this problem uh the first one is
L LSPs language server protocols they're
kind of the
um oneoff approach right so given a
symbol in code uh this language server
protocol it's an open source you can
check it out um in GitHub and the
Microsoft website will help you Traverse
uh your languages uh uh as and reach the
next area in which that code is either
referenced or defined um stag graph
actually works very similarly it's it's
what powers some of github's uh
Precision or search if you've seen it on
the right and tritter um is the same
thing but only in incrementally it can
kind of run through the entire codebase
you can kind of Mount it with more and
more context um the outlier here and all
of these are what I would call like
stattic code analyzers they have not a
lot to do with AI um all of these on one
side and the other one is is large
language models and large language
models are in the same bat because uh
you can essentially do the same thing
you can open your CH GPT or Cloud
console right now and uh you can insert
either a entire codebase or entire repo
and ask questions about how code is
defined and referenced um in specific
languages and unlike these static
analyzers um that build out or output a
a an abstra abstract syntax tree that
represents to the best of its ability um
the execution path um of a given code
language it's kind of It kind of works
like your interpreter or compiler um it
uses um uh language to understand the
definitions and references so if it's
visible um uh then uh then then there's
a good likelihood uh um the models will
capture it and uh we'll talk about
benchmarking now and you can see what
I'm talking
[Music]
about um so this is a kind of a early
phase um um part of our research uh back
in uh the beginning of
2024 uh we use skip which is uh the
extension or the augment of the indexing
protocol that's that's uh available to
the Microsoft
projects and we used it to analyze Java
repos um and it um and it's effective it
uh does a good job for um for a variety
of kind of standard use cases um but uh
as always it's imperfect we found a
variety of uh areas in which we had
expected this uh to be much more
accurate for example local variable
handling uh which was uh severely
limited uh the other one was a package
structure track tracking uh that was
also somewhat foundationally flawed we
found it to Output uh lines of zero uh
for some Java elements um we might uh
contribute a fix to that as well and um
and despite our work arounds it it it
just couldn't work for all of the
languages that we were interested in in
uh sorting and
ordering my second example is a Tre
sitter treit is a very popular project
it's a great incremental study code
scanning uh tool it's used by a lot of
security um static analyzers including
my uh my old team uh that uses a subset
of it um it's great creating um
snapshots um and we sought out to
Benchmark it against a rust project our
project is kind of a combination of um
some core core capabilities in Rust
that's now augmented by the usual
JavaScript and python for specific use
cases um again uh for some use cases we
found it was successfully able to parse
the basic structs in fields the field
types it helped us establish the
reliable parent children relationships
that we had expected to get um but it it
it was also somewhat flawed that uh the
imper functions couldn't be mapped to
their parent structs um and uh found uh
and intended to uh to break the entire
the entire chain uh we found multi-line
use statements also caused the identif
identifier splitting issues um in some
cases and um essentially we looked at
different ways to combine um something
like a skip that's really good at
specific languages but it actually for
some languages it runs the compiler Runs
The Interpreter which we didn't really
like um with triter to get some optimal
results because there was some overlap
but you can see it's an imperfect uh
imper no Silver Bullet right not
imperfect end result and the static
tools didn't really get us to where we
wanted and then we started to check out
um GPT 4.40 um uh this work um started
uh a good six probably five six months
back um and we had a benchmark right we
had the Benchmark of um how the static
analyzers are able to uh Traverse
through the in specific languages and we
were able to see what the gaps are um
and we were initially pleasantly
surprised we found that a full spectrum
of Def definitions was available and the
um multilanguage support was much better
better than we thought I mean uh think
of uh these models as essentially being
able to support any language I would
assume that even very new languages
would get great results for everything
like variable assignments constructs
aliases Etc um but reference ma matching
uh was the biggest problem so what llms
do not do is they don't Traverse the
graph un like the tools that I mentioned
previously um they input a um a a piece
of code and um they will essentially
read it and use the probabilistic mod
the same one that they would use to
write a beautiful love song they would
use that same probabilistic model um to
explain the code back to us as
users so by relying on llms only for
that direct string matching we actually
fail to handle some of the most common
pattern like aliases paralyzed name
contextual method calls and a few
others um so uh unfortunately this
wasn't a great kind of end result for
This research um but it did get us to a
point where I think um it's worth uh
worth spending some time on um I call
this the PO request grammar gradient and
I'll I'll go to my U my last version of
it because uh my time is kind of
starting to run out uh but it
essentially breaks down the areas in
which we found the different models to
be very good at or actually um not as
good as we expected so uh there's three
sections here one of it is probably the
most human or manual area which is the
review and suggestion uh uh human
feedback loop second one is testing and
feedback and fixes and the one is and
the last one is uh deploying the code
into a production system and using
things like integration and CI builds to
uh to troubleshoot it and you can see
that in each one of these sections we
found specific areas in which um um the
deterministic model combined with the
llms could actually make the difference
um so let's take the the bottom uh the
bottom section the semantics and
conventions um surprisingly the area
where humans are especially interested
in or focused on um not the area where
AI is the best um logical and syntactic
correctness is actually an area where AI
excels input a log output log in from CI
um in a bash format ask for the best way
to fix it uh you'll get an act a pretty
accurate response and the last one is
coherence this is where uh we use models
to try to help us understand whether or
not code will eventually impact existing
artifacts in production so this is
interesting we can take different types
of attributes of how code eventually
gets manifested into services and
infrastructures and apis um and ask AI
whether or not they'll be impacted
whether or not they'll be making
breaking
changes um so that's what we saw uh we
saw that the human Reviewer is generally
good at um the left side of uh um of
this uh uh of this model the AI reviewer
begins to uh begins to be very efficient
on uh Tex testing and fixes and actually
outperform the static models when it
cames to to coherence um and uh there's
a lot of more research that we have
lined up based on this work um I'd like
to shout out my colleague uh Hower um
this this is his giabellas and his
LinkedIn profile he's been leading some
of this uh exciting work you can see
some of the um uh work that he did to
understand large uh scale code bases
using um uh sequence um analysis using a
variety of these static and dynamic
tools as well as some of the um more
complex large code based uh research
that he's been doing um for for the past
uh past few months um yeah I think uh
that's uh generally
time thank you for for listening
in awesome well thank you very much sky
that was a really really interesting
session um yeah I'll invite anyone to to
ask some uh ask some questions in the
chat and we'll uh we'll we'll ask guy to
uh to to ask answer those um where would
people want to where should people go
guy what would you say the kind of like
next steps for people to to kind of get
more involved um I think uh I would
really encourage people to test out um
um the existing models with their
existing uh code bases uh both on the
public consoles uh try to feed a file a
diff your entire repo and ask questions
ask you know claw 3.5 Sonet and see what
types of results you'll find and start
to get the feel of where these models
really Excel and where where the gaps
are and if you really want to geek out
um I would really check out some of
these um static analyzers like Tre
sitter um and uh and Skip and try to use
their output as a potential input for uh
for your prompts so for example ask ask
you know AI to now help you figure out
what's going to get broken in some kind
of uh diff um that uh that was analyzed
by something like a treesitter and see
if you get better results compared to
what you've seen previously amazing uh
we got a question in from Richard um see
Richard wants to see the world burn see
he wants to know what are the what's the
worst ordering of the data you saw for
model performance let's start with the
worst um worst um AI models so probably
uh previous generation of uh of the open
AI models just before for for for o it
was very uh clear Before 40 that the
model wasn't even trying to consistently
parse out um common code structs like we
see it par now and now if you I mean
we're like light years away from where
we saw that uh about a year maybe nine
months back right yeah yeah and SS are
the
best um the best is probably so there's
two two parts that answer uh we found um
that 01 is uh the best at um finding or
answering questions around um the
maintenance of a convention so if we
asked if we get if we got 01 to
understand um let's say uh the uh
contract or the API spec of a program it
was the best at figuring out whether or
not a change will generate a downstream
impact that could result in a breaking
change yeah uh from interpretability and
explainability perspective this won't
surpris anyone I think anthropics 3.5
Sonet is the best we've seen so far it's
incrementally good compared to the last
version and um that's probably the model
I would of generally start with yeah
interesting and do you find much of a
difference or any variance in local
models to Cloud models or not much oh oh
yeah um the we we've tested some of the
small scale models um uh the instruct
you know the massive instruct models and
uh you can't compare it's uh the
unfortunately uh the commercial models
in this type of work where where context
is a kind of multivariant it could be a
Json that describes an A A diff that's
kind of written in kind of a git output
and code that could be written in
anything from a yaml to a python file um
unfortunately the open source models are
not as good as the commercial ones yeah
okay makes sense um have question from
Min um I think this is probably we can
answer this you know specifically from
from your own experience but I think
this is kind of like fairly general
question in terms of General usage of
llms any privacy security concerns for
feeding company Cod and
models um definitely an area of interest
in my past life um I'll first state the
obvious I think given the level of um um
efficiency we are bound to get from
these models especially for coding I
think it's inevitable that we will take
on some of that exposure over time I've
worked at large companies like paral
networks that currently I've learned use
Source graphs Cod I mean if par networks
have done their research modeling and
found out that uh you know uh the
lemon's worth the The Squeeze I would I
would definitely advise and you know
everybody out on my team is already need
deep in co-pilots and cursors and
everything and are just you 10xs better
yeah yeah and and I'd probably just add
to that um you know talk talk to your
own legal teams as well uh if you're if
you're working for a large company uh
talk to your own companies legal teams
they will very likely have advice for
you in terms of what you can and can't
use that in that space as
well uh I think we're are we out of
questions I think we're out of questions
now um guy uh why don't we uh let me
move your session off screen um thank
you very much guy really insightful
actually a very very interesting session
which which is truly truly practical in
terms of how we can actually get the
best and the most out of what we have
today of course llms and so forth will
get better and better and better over
time but we always need to get get the
most out of that and I think the uh the
ordering the prompts the context are
just just key for us to understand how
to get the most out of those these
systems so thank you very very much very
very very uh very very good session
thank you thank you Simon and and Shout
Out tesle team for uh putting this
together we don't have enough uh
opportunities to kick out about these
sorts of things and it's really where
the world's heading so great keep it
coming thank you so much appreciate that